Chapter 95.
The cassac.
Had you stepped on board the Peekquad at a certain juncture of this
postmortemizing of the whale, and had you strolled forward nigh the windless,
pretty sure am I, that you would have scanned with no small curiosity a very
strange enigmatical object which you would have seen there lying along
lengthwise in the Lee scuppers. Not the wondrous sistern in the whale's huge
head, not the prodigy of his unhinged lower jaw, not the miracle of his
symmetrical tail. None of these would so surprise you as half a glimpse of that
unaccountable cone, longer than a Kuckian as tall, nigh a foot in diameter
at the base, and jet black as Yojo, the ebony idol of Queig. And an idol indeed
it is. Or rather in old times its likeness was such an idol as that found
in the secret groves of Queen Maha in Judea. And for worshiping which King
Assa her son did depose her and destroyed the idol and burnt it for an
abomination at the brook Kedrron as darkly set forth in the 15th chapter of
the first book of Kings. Look at the sailor called the mincer who now comes
along and assisted by two allies heavily backs the grandmimus as mariners call it
and with bowed shoulders staggers off with it as if he were a grenadier
carrying a dead comrade from the field.
Extending it upon the folkal deck he now proceeds cylindrically to remove its
dark pelt as an African hunter the pelt of a boa. This done, he turns the pelt
inside out like a pantaloon leg, gives it a good stretching so as almost a
double its diameter, and at last hangs it well spread to the rigging to dry.
Air long it is taken down. When removing some 3 ft of it towards the pointed
extremity, and then cutting two slits for armholes at the other end, he
lengthwise slips himself bodily into it.
The mincer now stands before you invested in the full canonicals of his
calling. Imemorial to all his order.
This investature alone will adequately protect him while employed in the
peculiar functions of his office.
That office consists in mincing the horse pieces of blubber for the pots, an
operation which is conducted at a curious wooden horse, planted endwise
against the ball works, and with a capacious tub beneath it, into which the
minced pieces drop fast as the sheets from a wrapped orator's desk. Array in
decent black, occupying a conspicuous pulpit, intent on Bible leaves. What a
candidate for an archbishop Rick. What a lad for a pope were this mincer.
Footnote. Bible leaves. Bible leaves.
This is the invariable cry from the mates to the mincer. It enjoins him to
be careful and cut his work into as thin slices as possible. In as much as by so
doing the business of boiling out the oil is much accelerated, and its
quantity considerably increased, besides perhaps improving it in quality.
End of footnote.